DIEGO CUEVAS

Frontend developer.

Bogotá, DC

+573202680705 -- ingdcuevas@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/diego-fernando-cuevas-frontend-developer https://github.com/Dfcuevas -- https://diegocuevaspage.netlify.app

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Frontend developer with more than 2 years of experience creating attractive and functional user interfaces. Expert in HTML, CSS, JavaScript and modern frameworks such as React. Committed to optimizing web application performance and improving user experience.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

FRONT END DEVELOPER | 06/2024 - 08/2024

Medical Appointment App – Bogotá D.C.

- Fullstack application developed to schedule, reschedule and cancel medical appointments, in which patients can register, through a form designed in detail to collect patient information, as well as the doctor they want to see them.
- The application is developed on Appwrite, which allows us to implement databases, storage, authentication and messaging to our application.
- Platform administrators can modify the available appointments and any modification will be informed to the patient via text message, using Twilio.

FRONT END DEVELOPER | 07/2024 - 07/2024

Twitter Clone App – Bogotá D.C

- Fullstack application developed on the front with React, TailwindCss, React Query, React hot toast, react router dom and DaisyUI, and the back was developed with NodeJs, Express, MongoDB, mongoose, jsonwebtoken, cloudinary and bcryptJs.
- An important feature to highlight is the protection of routes both in the backend and in the front. For the backend, a middleware was implemented that verifies through JWT if a token exists to allow the user access to the different endpoints of the server.
- The Users, Posts, and Authentication models were implemented using MongoDB with the help of Mongoose to structure, organize, and validate the information.

EDUCATION

Soy Henry – Fullstack Developer Web Development, 01/2022 – 11/2022

Platzi – Frontend Architect

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming languages: HTML, CSS, Development Tools: Webpack, NPM. **JavaScript**

Frameworks and Libraries: React,

TailwindCSS, ThreeJs, GSAP.

Web Development, 01/2021 - 06/2021

University of Pamplona

Telecommunications Engineer 09/2015

Tests: Jest.

Version control: Git, GitHub, Bitbucket

LANGUAGES

Spanish: Native - **English:** Upper Intermediate (B2)